<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zentangent</title>
    <description>The musings of a young feminist/artist/engineer Buckle up and come along for the ride
</description>
    <link>http://www.zentangent.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.zentangent.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:41:46 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:41:46 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Make Something Ugly</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ugly/ugly1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My pal Munster&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little over a month ago, inspiration struck. I was “cleaning” my room when I grabbed two thrift store finds and upon seeing them side by side an idea was born. I hadn’t made a stuffed animal in 2-3 years and my skills then were amateur at best, but in one moment I became convinced that I could create a perfect plushie monster. It would be adorable and endearing in a sort of off-putting nuanced way. Basically it would be the Zooey Deschanel New Girl of stuffed animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is, I wanted it to be both brilliant and fast - easy but also perfect. It only took until after I had seam-ripped the garments for me to realize I was in over my head. By the time I had a few limbs stitched and stuffed I already didn’t want to look at this project ever again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be the understatement of the year to say that I have project commitment issues. In my room there is a whole drawer dedicated to years of unfinished crafts. If it was up to me, Munster would be a set of arms and legs in that drawer, but it wasn’t up to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One aspect of my diagnosed mental illness, is to put it plainly, extreme and constant instability. So, when my case manager heard about my newly adopted and abandoned project, heard how quickly my joy turned to frustration turned to absolute disdain, she gave me a homework assignment. She gave it to me week after week, as I ignored her request. Finish the damn stuffed animal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t want to. I didn’t want to so badly that I argued and fought against it. I refused, declaring it a brave act of protest, when in fact it was my status quo, to abandon any project that I feared might reveal my imperfections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I inevitably cracked and finished Munster, but I didn’t do so joyfully. For about 20 minutes a week, usually right before an appointment I would sew at raging speeds and hot glue so sloppily I burnt every fingertip in a rushed attempt to get this over with. Then one day, as I sat on the floor of my room, trapped in a hot glue spider web, stepping on pins in an attempt to escape, I looked down to realize he was done. He wasn’t polished or pretty, but he had four limbs, a face, and no holes big enough for his bodily stuffing to escape through. I could say I was finished, and it felt really &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ugly/uglydetails.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Munster&#39;s Details&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It felt so good in fact, that after 5 months, I am finally writing my second blog post. The reality is that my insatiable desire for perfection holds me back in everything I do. There are over a dozen half-written articles that inevitably didn’t make the cut. Thet were deleted the minute I began to doubt their worth. This craving for perfection seeps into my art in the most devious of ways. Even in the privacy of my own room, even knowing that no one ever has to see what I am making, I still become paralyzed by the fear of imperfection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finishing Munster wasn’t about improving my skills. It wasn’t about making something that I was proud of. It wasn’t even about learning to control my fits of anger and frustration. It was just a big middle finger to the critic in my head to say “Yeah, I can make shitty stuff and the world won’t end.” It was about the catharsis of hating something and doing it anyway. It was about stripping my skin and exiting my comfort zone so I could get back to what I always wanted to do and just make. You should try it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make something ugly. Make it in a fit of rage or frustration. Sew too fast. Rip fabric or paper. Draw even if you can’t see a damn thing, because you’re sobbing like the hot mess you are. The ugly thing and the ugly process can be such a relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Munster is sitting on a shelf behind me as I type. As a finishing touch, I cut back open his mouth and gave him zipper teeth. He has become the physical manifestation of all of my worst fears and self-doubt. When my thoughts become too much I’ve begun to write them on scraps, crumple them up and feed them to Munster. In fact I have just fed him a hearty writers-fear lunch. I fed him the fear that my words aren’t worth reading. I fed him the fear that I am both too boring and over-dramatic – that every metaphor I use is a cliché or that my best work I stole from the tongues of dead authors who I will never be as good as.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ugly/uglyfed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Feeding Munster&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a really bad day I’ll feed him the fear that all of my friends have forgotten me. Or the fear that everyone eventually leaves. I am told that after years of therapy, the evil voice in my head will at least quiet to a faint hum. Until I learn how to tame my demons or send them off for good, I can at least feed them to Munster. I can write them down, get them out, and seal them away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as it turns out I love my ugly, terrible Munster. I hope you take the time to make something ugly yourself and then feel how beautiful that can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Loving and hating the ugly imperfect journey to Zen&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;-Chelsea&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 18:22:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.zentangent.com/2016/03/23/make-something-ugly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.zentangent.com/2016/03/23/make-something-ugly.html</guid>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        <category>random</category>
        
        <category>art</category>
        
        <category>mental health</category>
        
        <category>crafting</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello, World!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, world! Or more accurately small subset of the world who would entertain themselves by reading my blog. Have you ever been curious about the origin of writing programs to output “Hello, world!” as a means to learn new syntax or test your development environment? Honestly, I wasn’t until I titled this blog post, but it turns out it’s actually pretty &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%22Hello,_World!%22_program#History&quot;&gt;interesting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that seems like enough stalling, onward with the obligatory introduction. As a social-anxiety ridden introvert who hates talking about herself I’m probably the last person who should be writing a blog, but ideally after this post the blog will be a lot less about me and a lot more about topics that get me fired up! “And what are those topics?” I hear you inquire through your computer screen. Well dilligent reader, I’m so glad you asked! Topics I may write about include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gender &amp;amp; sexuality issues&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the future of databases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;education reform&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mental illness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;artsy shit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;social justice issues&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cool code stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically this blog is a bucket I’m putting under my brain to catch every bit and piece that falls out. Oh, and before signing off, it might be helpful for you to know who I am. If you couldn’t care less about the following anecdotes feel free to shoot straight down to the comments section and give me feedback! I have plenty ideas of what I want to write about, but I want to know what &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; want to &lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt; about. So if you’re still reading, because you’re curious about who I am or what makes me tick, allow me to present &lt;em&gt;Fun facts about Chelsea in list form&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As a child I collected small dog figurines.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the 3rd grade I wanted my birthday party to be morgue themed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I was young all I wanted to be when I grew up was a working woman in Manhattan, who rollerbladed to work and had a messenger bag.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first time I ate an orange I was 19.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sylvia Plath is one of my idols (and she and I have spent time in the same psychiatric unit).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m currently in my old-school Taylor Swift phase of music writing, watch out ex-boyfriends!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I identify as pansexual and a cis-gendered female.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m writing these facts as they randomly come to mind.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I cried while watching the documentary &lt;em&gt;Who Killed the Electric Car&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m reallly good at starting things and pretty bad at finishing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on that note, I’ll call that list done. If this blog starts to grow too big for its britches, I’ll probably make an &lt;em&gt;About Me&lt;/em&gt; page and add the option to filter posts by category or tags. Until then, hope you’re excited to keep reading and come along for the ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Until next time, stay zen! Or at least live tangent to it.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;-Chelsea&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 18:22:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.zentangent.com/general/2015/10/19/hello-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.zentangent.com/general/2015/10/19/hello-world.html</guid>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        <category>random</category>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
